you try sticking your pick in and moving
it around but you're not sure what
you're doing or if you're even hitting
the right pins instead of getting upset
get your key and stick it all the way to
the back next we're gonna mark where the
key meets the key way you could use a
pencil but sharpie will be easier to see
for educational purposes mine is a
little extra girthy a fine point marker
will give you thinner more accurate
lines the valleys or cuts in the key not
only tell you how many pins you are
working with but the depth of the cuts
or the keys bidding tells you how the
lock is pinned think of your key like a
password that you carry around with you
you stingy bastards won't even share
your netflix login with family but
you'll share your home login with the
world align the tip of your pick with
the last cut on the key and use the
reference mark we made before getting
distracted to create a new reference
mark on your pick continue doing this
for each cut until you've marked all of
your lock's pin positions
whoosh now all you have to do is align
these marks with the front of the keyway
and you'll know exactly where each pin
position is when you practice picking a
lock